Finding Aid for the Anne Waldman Papers, 1945-2012
Anne Waldman Papers
- Writing
  - Poetry
    - Published Work
      - Alphabetical File
        - No Hassles
          - "Drafts: No Hassles & others" (Box 30)
          - Illustrations and poems (Box 30)
        - Not a Male Pseudonym, with drawings by Julia Connor (2 folders), 1974, 1980, 1989-1990 (Box 30)
        - Notes on Sitting Beside a Noble Corpse (Box 30)
        - On the Wing, with others, 1968 (Box 30)
        - Polar Ode, with Eileen Myles, 1972 (Box 30)
        - Polemical Poems, with Jack Collom, Anselm Hollo, 1997 (Box 30)
        - The Quenching of the Lamp: Versions from the Therigatha and Theragatha, with Andrew Schelling (may include material from Songs of the Sons and Daughters of Buddha, another volume of selected translations from the Therigatha and the Theragatha ) (Box 30)
        - Self-Portrait, with Joe Brainard, 1971 (Box 30)
        - Shaman (includes correspondence with Jürgen Schmidt, 1989) (Box 30)
        - Skin Meat Bones
          - Poems, alphabetical order, A-R (Box 30)
          - Poems, alphabetical order, S-Z (Box 30)
          - Nichole Thiel score and other material: correspondence, publicity, copies of cover art, reviews, notes, ca. 1985-1986 (Box 30)
        - Sleep Shade: draft, undated (Box 30)
        - Snoring in New York: sonnet sequence (Box 30)
        - Songs of the Sons and Daughters of Buddha, with Andrew Schelling (some folders comprised of loose poems found throughout the collection; also includes material from The Quenching of the Lamp and Monks and Nuns, which are other volumes of selected translations from the Theragatha and the Therigatha )
          - Clean draft (Box 31)
          - Annotated draft (Box 31)
          - Monks and Nuns short version (Box 31)
          - Miscellaneous drafts (Box 31)
        - Speak Gently in Her Bardo, with Susan Noel (Box 31)
        - Sphinxeries: "Originals of Sphinxeries" (Box 31)
        - Suffer the Mysterium, 1993 (Box 31)
        - Sun the Blond Out (Box 31)
        - Tell Me About It: Poems for Painters, 1989 (Box 31)
        - 31 Leaves for Autumn, undated (Box 31)
        - Troubairitz
          - Correspondence regarding translation 1998-2002 (Box 31)
          - "Xerox of working draft of Troubairitz & original notebook…" (original at the New York Public Library) (Box 31)
          - "A's Look Early Draft of Troubairitz " [also called "A's Book"], undated (Box 31)
          - Troubariste, "draft one of many," 1992 (Box 31)
          - "Troubariste (Troubairitz)," 1992, undated (Box 31)
          - Notes on vocabulary, 2001 and undated (Box 31)
        - Up Thru the Years, 1970 (Box 31)
        - Unidentified partial manuscript, and later, ca. 1985 (Box 31)
          (unpublished "selected"?)
        - West Indies Poems, 1971 (Box 31)
      - Collaborations (Anne Waldman with…)
        - Ted Berrigan. Memorial Day (2 folders), 1971 (Box 31)
        - Joe Brainard interviews, undated (Box 31)
          (includes "DeWarr's Profile")
        - Franco Beltrametti, Reed Bye, Suse Hahn, Harry Hoogstraten. Hanging Out in Amsterdam, 1978 (Box 31)
        - Reed Bye (Box 31)
          (originally Reed Bye's folders)
        - Jack Collom, Chris Collom, Phil Garrison, et al. various collaborations, 1972-1980 (Box 31)
        - "Collaborations with Anne," undated (Box 31)
        - Reed Bye, Douglas Dunn. The Secret of the Waterfall
          - Drafts, notes, publicity material (2 folders) (Box 31)
          - Program, printed material, clippings (Box 31)
          - "Originals": drafts (Box 31)
        - Jayne Cortez and Cara Benson, 2009 (Box 31)
        - Allen Ginsberg, Zen Mountain Monastery. Wide Awake Writing, April 27-29, 1990 (Box 31)
        - Bernadette Mayer, "The Basketball Article": ephemera and related, includes untitled piece re women's basketball (Box 31)
        - Althea Schelling. Desdemona. Erudite Fangs Editions, 2007 (Box 31)
        - Andrew Schelling et al., Sources of Poetry with Anne Waldman and Andrew Schelling, Zen Mountain Monastery, April 10-12, 1992 (Box 31)
        - Vajra Regent Osel Tendzin, Poems 1985, undated (Box 31)
        - Ann Wilson. Solo Pablo Rimbeau: "performance which included reading of 'Fast Speaking Woman'," undated (Box 31)
        - Noah Saterstrom. Soldatesque/Soldiering with Dreams of Wartime. Draft, undated (Box 31)
        - Randy Roark. One Night, 2001 (Box 31)
          Published in a limited edition of 500, 26 of which are lettered and signed. A and W editions included.
        - Steir, Pat. Cry Stall Gaze. Drafts, undated (Box 31)
      - Translations
        - Mahmoud Darwish (Box 31)
        - Mercedes Durand, "Nonsyntactical Jazz" (Box 31)
        - Nizar Qabanni, ca. 1988 (Box 31)
      - Iovis, Bk. I ( Iovis: All Is Full of Jove)
        - Notes, Drafts, and Research Material, ca. 1960s, 1978-1990
          - Bennington College Notebook: Myth, Ritual, and Literature with Stanley Edgar Hyman (Box 32)
          - Questions for men for Iovis (Box 32)
          - Other (16 folders) (Box 32)
        - Collated Drafts
          - Early version, Cantos I-XIII (2 folders) (Box 32)
          - Iovis I-XIV, 1990 (Box 32)
          - Iovis I-XIV, 1990-1991 (Box 32)
            (signed)
          - Iovis Omnia Plena, Early Draft, ca. 1990-1992 (Box 32)
          - Iovis Omnia Plena: "Thread Through the maze," I-XXI, 1990-1993
            - I-IX, pp. 1-114 (Box 32)
            - X-XXI, pp. 115-256 (Box 32)
          - Faxed proofs, December 14, 1992 (Box 33)
          - Loose numbered pages (Box 33)
          - Miscellaneous drafts and older work, undated (Box 33)
      - Iovis, Bk. II ( Iovis Book Two)
        - Notes, Drafts, and Research Material
          - Correspondence
            - William Sterling re Latin translations, 1994-1995 (Box 33)
            - Peter Lamborn Wilson (a.k.a. Hakim Bey): "blurb for Iovis?," undated (Box 33)
            - Correspondence re Iovis I and/or used in Iovis II 1984-1997, undated (Box 33)
          - Note tablets, undated (Box 33)
          - Nuclear power clippings and poem draft, 1989 (Box 33)
            (unclear whether for Bk. I or II)
          - So Help Me Sappho, typescript (Box 33)
          - Writings by Ambrose and others, undated (Box 33)
          - Proofs and drafts, undated (Box 33)
          - Includes sketch by Ambrose (Box 33)
          - Includes acrostic poem by Ambrose (Box 33)
          - Includes letter written by Anne Waldman's grandfather, John Waldman, Sr., and copy of "Evangelle," an account of a trip to Ken Kesey's farm (Box 33)
          - Other (12 folders), ca. 1976-1995 (Box 33)
        - Full Drafts and Proofs
          - Early version (2 folders), undated (Box 33)
          - Collated draft, undated
            - pp. 1-14 (Box 34)
            - Added-in pages (Box 34)
            - pp. 45-79 (Box 34)
            - pp. 80-146 (Box 34)
            - pp. 147-206 (Box 34)
            - pp. 207-239 plus additional materials (Box 34)
            - pp. 240-274 (Box 34)
          - Table of Contents: loose page, version unknown (Box 34)
          - Spiral-bound draft, undated
            - I-X: pp. 1-111 (Box 34)
            - XI-XIX: pp. 112-215 (Box 34)
            - XX-XXVIII/Coda: pp. 126-295 (Box 34)
          - Copy: Publisher's copy proofs, 1996
            - I-V: publisher's correspondence, front matter, pp. 1-56 (Box 34)
            - VI-XIII: pp. 57-139 (Box 34)
            - XIV-XVIII: pp. 140-200 (Box 34)
            - XIX-Coda: pp. 201-266 (Box 34)
          - Edited copy: edited at Coffee House Press, ca. 1996-1997
            - Publisher's correspondence, front matter, pp. 1-96 (Box 34)
            - pp. 97-192 (Box 34)
            - pp. 193-288 (Box 34)
            - pp. 289-384 (Box 34)
          - Proofs (4 folders), ca. 1996-1997
            - I-V: publisher's correspondence, front matter, pp. 1-68 (Box 34)
            - VI-XII: pp. 69-163 (Box 34)
            - XIII-XVIII: pp. 164-242 (Box 34)
            - XIX-end: pp. 243-324, plus illustrations and miscellaneous additions and corrections (Box 34)
      - Iovis, Bk. III: draft entitled "Exclusion 'Dark Arcana's' Imbroglio," parts of a journal kept in North Vietnam (2 folders), May 2000 (Box 34)
      - Iovis, Bk. III drafts and notes (2 folders), undated (Box 34)
      - The Iovis Trilogy: Colors in the Mechanism of Concealment, notes and drafts, 2011 (Box 34)
      - Kill or Cure 1994
        - Early Version
          - Foreword: "A Note on This Book" (Box 35)
          - Table of Contents: includes most of the poems from this list (Box 35)
          - Contents: includes other poems, in table of contents order (Box 35)
          - Not in table of contents (Box 35)
        - Draft: pp. 1-84 (Box 35)
        - Draft: pp. 1-206 (Box 35)
        - Drafts/Collected Poems
          - A-K (Box 35)
          - L-P (Box 35)
          - R-W (Box 35)
          - Miscellaneous and fragments (Box 35)
        - Oficina Legal de la Mujer: publication from Christian Santos in Nicaragua, referenced in "Managua Sketches" (Box 35)
        - "Credo" (Box 35)
        - Pieces used in Kill or Cure (Box 35)
        - Miscellaneous loose poems (Box 35)
        - Essays: "Mandala of Poetics," "The Poetics of Tibet," "Poetry as Energy, Siddhi, Terma: Notes," "The Sleepers," 1987, undated (Box 35)
        - Bound Proofs: inscribed by Anne, "Reading copy" (Box 35)
        - Bound Proofs, copy 2 (Box 35)
        - Cover (Box 35)
        - Galleys, April 1995
          - pp. iii-48 (Box 35)
          - pp. 49-129 (Box 35)
          - pp. 133-200 (Box 35)
          - pp.201-269 (Box 35)
        - Galleys, Manuscript and Layout Pages, April 1995
          - pp. 1-47 (Box 35)
          - pp. 48-100 (Box 35)
          - pp. 101-166 (Box 35)
          - pp. 167-235 (Box 35)
          - Final Art (Box 35)
        - Galleys: Rough Pages, March 1995
          - pp. iii-48 (Box 35)
          - pp. 49-132 (Box 35)
          - pp. 133-200 (Box 35)
          - pp.201-266 (Box 35)
        - Review lists, undated (Box 35)
      - Beat Roots. Drafts and correspondence. Illustrated by George Schneeman 2006 (Box 35)
      - In the Room of Never Grieve: New and Selected Poems, 1985-2003 (2 folders) 2008
        - Drafts
          - January 23, 2002, (2 folders) (Box 35)
          - July 17, 2003, (4 folders) (Box 36)
          - July 29, 2003, (4 folders) (Box 36)
          - July 31, 2003, (4 folders) (Box 36)
          - Undated, (4 folders) (Box 36)
      - Manatee/Humanity, 2009
        - Draft (2 folders), August 2008 (Box 36)
        - Drafts (8 folders), undated (Box 37)
    - Single Titles
      ("fl" stands for "first line")
      - A Basque (Box 37)
      - A Birthday Sonnet, for Dorothy Bye (by Anne Waldman and Reed Bye) (Box 37)
      - A Child's Garden of Verses (Box 37)
      - A Coney Island of the Mind [or "In highschool"], 1958 (Box 37)
      - A Daughter's Lament in May [?] [possibly for early version of Kill or Cure] (Box 37)
      - A decision has been reached! [fl] (Box 37)
      - A Drum & a Guitar & in a Painting by Picasso (Box 37)
      - A Guston, homage to Philip Guston, master painter (Box 37)
      - A Heart, For Ambrose (Box 37)
      - A Letter, March 21, 1991 (Box 37)
      - A man is humming a Spanish song: O the barrio I have not [fl] (Box 37)
      - A Moment's Tender Presence (Box 37)
      - A Name as Revery (Box 37)
      - A Slice at That (Box 37)
      - A stain of ignorance [fl--possibly forms part of larger work] (Box 37)
      - A Story About A Magician [and] A List for a Child (Box 37)
      - Abortion (Box 37)
      - Abrochese el Cinturon de Seguridad (Box 37)
      - "Accrostic," plus "Sun Set Moon Up," and by Lenika Miosol Vazaquez, "On a Plane Flight," August 6, 1987 (Box 37)
      - Acrostic (Box 37)
      - Acoustical (Box 37)
      - "addiction" chant (Box 37)
      - Adventures in India (Box 37)
      - after Archilochos, for Anselm Hollo (Box 37)
      - After Campfire Ring Around the Moon September (Box 37)
      - After Praxilla (Box 37)
      - After Sappho (Box 37)
      - After the Greek [or "After the Greek Anthology"] (Box 37)
      - After the Lament of the Flutes for Tammuz (Box 37)
      - After-Dinner Entertaining [exists also in a slightly different version as "Midnight Snacks"] (Box 37)
      - Agrippa (Box 37)
      - Ali (Box 37)
      - Alice Annual [or "Annual Alice"] (Box 37)
      - All Hands (Box 37)
      - All the Past Is Silence (Box 37)
      - After Hadewijc (Box 37)
      - All This Every Day [book review; book by Joanne Kyger] (Box 37)
      - Alphabet Cali (Box 37)
      - Alphabeto Sudamericano (Box 37)
      - Always guessed and later knew [fl; includes other poems, from folder labeled "drafts & discarded Poems 1976-1980] (Box 37)
      - Ambapali Speaks [from the Therigatha or the Theragatha ] (Box 37)
      - Amendment 2 (Box 37)
      - American Birds (Box 37)
      - American Manners [photocopy from published work] (Box 37)
      - American Mythology (Box 37)
      - American Renter (Box 37)
      - An Accent O Each Shape (Box 37)
      - Anarchy Reggae (Box 37)
      - Ancient Song Rising (Box 37)
      - Andrew's Birthday (Box 37)
      - Anne la Morn (Box 37)
      - Appetite (Box 37)
      - April Dream [note attached "from Kill or Cure"] (Box 37)
      - Arioso (Box 37)
      - Around the House [partial?] (Box 37)
      - Artemis (Box 37)
      - Artist Room (Box 37)
      - As (Certain) Blue (Box 37)
      - Asleep In Your Arms (Box 37)
      - Aspetti un Momento! (Box 37)
      - At 47 Fall '72 Reflect Colombia NY Express [?] [Originally "Conquer"] (Box 37)
      - At midnight wanted to be with just one [fl] (Box 37)
      - Athens (Box 37)
      - Autodidact [or "Acrostic"] (Box 37)
      - Autumn Poem [or "Autumn Fall Poem," "Leaves"; for Rocky Ledge ?] (Box 37)
      - Ayansem [or "Ansem"], for Jane Hollo (Box 37)
      - Azalea Blooming Today (Box 37)
      - Baby Breakdown, for Bill Berkson (Box 37)
      - Baby's Pantoum (Box 37)
      - Backyard Poems (Box 37)
      - Bali [includes various versions or related works?] (Box 37)
      - Ballade (Box 37)
      - Balzac (Box 37)
      - Barbara (Box 37)
      - Bardo Corridor [a version also appears as "Corridoror"] (Box 37)
      - Be Happy O Sad World (Box 37)
      - Be kind economists [fl] (Box 37)
      - Bean Sprouts for Phil Whalen [title?] (Box 37)
      - Bedroom Shadow (Box 37)
      - Beethoven's Birthday [plus poem "Steven"; also includes version entitled "On Beethoven's Birthday," from a folder labeled "c. 1976-1980"] (Box 37)
      - Bellini (Box 37)
      - Bench [or "Johnny Bench"] (Box 37)
      - Bernoulli Effect Song (Box 37)
      - Berthe Morisot (Box 37)
      - Big Atlantic Purse (Box 37)
      - Bird with the Herd [by Larry Fagin and Anne Waldman] (Box 37)
      - Bluehawk (Box 37)
      - Bobbie Louise (Box 37)
      - Bonnie rode Molly the palomino up here one [fl] (Box 37)
      - Books You All Should Read (Box 37)
      - Boots for A Black Hat Dancer (Box 37)
      - Born Again Blues (Box 37)
      - Both, Both (Box 37)
      - Brautigan (Box 37)
      - Breakfast (Box 37)
      - Breathe in the malady, the malaise, the warnings of the megalopolis citadels [fl] (Box 37)
      - Bremen (Box 37)
      - Bride (Box 37)
      - Brinks of Fame: Monologue (Box 37)
      - Buddha Family Qualities [with subtitle or alternate title "Ratna"] (Box 37)
      - Bye (Box 37)
      - Cabal [one version missing p. 2] (Box 37)
      - Cabin [one version missing pp. 1-2] (Box 37)
      - Cabin Dreams (Box 37)
      - Call to the Good Roof Dream (Box 37)
      - Can't Touch This [missing p. 4] (Box 37)
      - Cantilena (Box 37)
      - Canyon [early title "Drive up Canyon"] (Box 37)
      - Canyon Lessons Narration ["End of Romance" separate or part of poem?] (Box 37)
      - Canzone (Box 37)
      - Cats & Dogs (Box 37)
      - CBGB's, Mudd Club [fl] (Box 37)
      - Celestial Black & White (Box 37)
      - Cento [plus fragment?] (Box 37)
      - Chair (for The End of Time) (Box 37)
      - Chicago (Box 37)
      - Child Chant (Box 37)
      - Childish Ode to the Journalists of the Hackneyed Poetry World [final title?] (Box 37)
      - Child's Poem (Box 37)
      - Child's Story (Box 37)
      - Christmas Gists, for Reed (Box 37)
      - Circulin (Box 37)
      - Cittipatti Blues (Box 37)
      - City Suite [orig. called "NY Suite"] (Box 37)
      - Clark Late Birthday (Box 37)
      - Code: Intensification of Shade (Box 37)
      - Colors, for Michael Herrick (Box 37)
      - Complaint (Box 37)
      - Constellations (Box 37)
      - Contra Chant (Box 37)
      - Contraband [note attached " Blue Mosque: some rejected in final cuts"] (Box 37)
      - Correspondence (Box 37)
      - Coup de Grace (Box 37)
      - Credo (Box 37)
      - Crime Work, for Charlotte Carter (Box 37)
      - Crystals form rapidly [fl], for Reed Bye [prev. titles "Going Down", "Malachite"?] 1976 (Box 37)
      - curious [fl] (Box 37)
      - Curse [also called "Iran Contra Spell"] (Box 37)
      - Cutting/for Reed Bye (Box 37)
      - Cut up, Front Seat (Box 37)
      - D (Box 37)
      - Dance (Box 37)
      - Daughter's Lament in May (Box 37)
      - Dear Creeley [p. 14 doesn't seem to go with rest, but is all part of "Dear Creeley" section of Iovis I ] (Box 37)
      - Dear Luncheon Meat [letter, possibly to Douglas Dunn?] (Box 37)
      - Dear Mr. Madigan [fl; correspondence piece] (Box 37)
      - Dear Sky Box [partial] (Box 37)
      - Definition of Water Meditation [or "Legend of Desire to Rule Water"] (Box 37)
      - Demilitarized Zone [with subtitle or alternate titles "War" and "(Redonda)"] (Box 37)
      - Democracy (Box 37)
      - Demon Chant (Box 37)
      - Denyse DuRoi's poems are complex weaves, meanderings [fl; review or blurb] (Box 37)
      - Desert Storm [or "Tormiento del Deserto"?] (Box 37)
      - Desideratum (Box 37)
      - Dialogue [or "Dialogue: Conversation at Nine Thousand Feet"; one copy missing p. 1] (Box 37)
      - Diamond (Box 37)
      - Diatribe: A Curse (Box 37)
      - Discourse Coloradan [copy 3 has p. 1 only] (Box 37)
      - Distinct Ardent (Box 37)
      - Dopey Brains Awake (Box 37)
      - Dossier (Box 37)
      - Dramatic House (Box 37)
      - [Dream poems and narratives]
        - Dream [fl: Thickhead spring air"] (Box 37)
        - Dream [fl: "Last night I dream my bones are hollow"] (Box 37)
        - dream March 28.76 (Box 37)
        - Dream about being in two plays at Bennington… [fl; description of a dream] (Box 37)
        - April 19/20 (Box 37)
        - May 4 (Box 37)
        - Morning May 4 (Box 37)
        - dream/ smoke tobacco [first two lines] (Box 37)
      - Drugs (Box 37)
      - Dual it ee [or "Duality"' plus other poems and notes] (Box 37)
      - Dying (Box 37)
      - Early June in Colorado (Box 37)
      - Echos (Box 37)
      - Edwin Denby on Gertrude Stein (Box 37)
      - E.E. UU (Box 37)
      - El Rito (Box 37)
      - Elegy, for Kate Berrigan Morrison (1965-1987) (Box 37)
      - Elysium (Box 37)
      - End of Spin (Box 37)
      - Epilogue [Anne Waldman's or other's?] (Box 37)
      - Epiphany (Box 37)
      - Epithalamium (Box 37)
      - especially if you sing it accurately, smiles [fl] (Box 37)
      - Esteem, for A.N. [Alice Notley] (Box 37)
      - Everything around is touched by her [fl; part of another poem?] (Box 37)
      - Eye Ball Movie (Box 37)
      - Eyes in All Heads to Be Looked out of [plus "Cut"] (Box 37)
      - Expiration after Donne (Box 37)
      - Extracts/Poems, Letters, Notes from a Journal [continues: "(South American) Colombia only July 6-August 6,/1972"; "published in The World"] (Box 37)
      - Falling in Love on Red Oaks Lane [and cutups; related?] (Box 37)
      - Fast Speaking Woman (Box 37)
      - February Ether: Sky's No Limit (Box 37)
      - First Winter Days (Box 37)
      - 5 Ghost of Days for Charles North (Box 37)
      - 5 Lovers in 5 Acts [short play] (Box 37)
      - Five Poems for Ron Padgett (Box 37)
      - Flat recurrent rain [fl] (Box 37)
      - for Alice Notley (Box 37)
      - for Frances (Box 37)
      - for Harry Smith (Box 37)
      - For Immediate of previous [cutup appropriation] January 6, 1976 (Box 37)
      - for Jimmy [includes notes, other poems?] (Box 37)
      - For Joan (Box 37)
      - For Reed (Box 37)
      - For Robert Creeley [or "for R.C."; p. 3 May not belong] (Box 37)
      - For Ruth [Ruth Sikelianos] (Box 37)
      - For Steven ["(Steven Lowe)"; in folder labeled "c. 1976-1980"] (Box 37)
      - for Ted Berrigan (Box 37)
      - Four Corners (Box 37)
      - Frances (Box 37)
      - Friday Night (Box 37)
      - From a Class Discussion, August 19, 1975 (Box 37)
      - (from a continuing work) in Spanish [fragments of larger work?] (Box 37)
      - from Iovis Omnia Plena (Box 37)
      - from A Palm Reading for ALW ? [notes from a palm reading] 1985 (Box 37)
      - from dream to dream to dream [fl; part of larger work?; includes Spanish translations] (Box 37)
      - from Shaman, to Bob Dylan (Box 37)
      - From the Dream Journal (Box 37)
      - Fuck Up (Box 37)
      - Genetics (Box 37)
      - George Schneeman Peoples the Sky (Box 37)
      - Glasnost (Box 37)
      - Glenn Branca (Box 37)
      - Goddess of Wisdom Whose Substance Is Desire, for Joanne Kyger (Box 37)
      - Granny in the Apple (Box 37)
      - Gringo (Box 37)
      - Grotte [from Iovis Omnia Plena] (Box 37)
      - Guest (Box 37)
      - Guise, for Lewis (Box 37)
      - Gut Convinced (Box 37)
      - Habanera ["for birthday of J.M.W."] (Box 37)
      - Hag of Beare (Caillech na Beara) ["Version by Anne Waldman & John Wright"] (Box 37)
      - Halloween (Box 37)
      - "Hannah's Ware" and "Alice's Street Near the Palace" in The Germ, 1998 (Box 37)
      - He (Box 37)
      - He sweeps in, little boxer [fl] (Box 37)
      - Hecate (Box 37)
      - Helping the Dreamer (Box 37)
      - Him (Box 37)
      - History (Box 37)
      - Holy Cows (Box 37)
      - Hopes & Fears [includes one version with attached note, "from Skin Meat Bones"] (Box 37)
      - House of the Senses (Box 37)
      - Housework [p. 2 related or no?] (Box 37)
      - How Does the Dalmatian Get Its Spots? (Box 37)
      - How I Became (Biblical) [Alternate title "North America"? Also called, "How I Became Biblical"] (Box 37)
      - How the Sestina (Yawn) Works (Box 37)
      - "I am blinded by a fiery circle," for James Schuyler (Box 37)
      - I Bow at Bodhgaya (Box 37)
      - I had such a mother [fl] (Box 37)
      - I Stand Humble Before That Standing Within Me Which Speaks with Me [fl?] (Box 37)
      - I tell you again, "My heart is pinched" [fl; last word unclear; part of larger work? By Anne Waldman?] (Box 37)
      - I wanna go [fl] (Box 37)
      - I went. I enjoyed myself. I went again--SM [fl; fragment?] (Box 37)
      - I Wept unto a Car (Box 37)
      - Icy Rose [attached note, "Made into Broadside"] (Box 37)
      - "If there's one thing I'm sick of…" [quotations; fragment?] (Box 37)
      - I'll take romance [fl; fragment?] (Box 37)
      - I'm far away from home [fl] (Box 37)
      - I've got a girl shadow [fl] (Box 37)
      - In a Public Place (Box 37)
      - In Being Musical (Box 37)
      - In Dusseldorf, however [fl; part of larger work?] (Box 37)
      - In Paterson (Box 37)
      - In Ruins: A dream (Box 37)
      - In the snowy night [fl; this poem crossed out; also includes "Heart's Dentist," or part of it] (Box 37)
      - In This Or Any Other (Box 37)
      - In Toronto (Box 37)
      - Inamorata (Box 37)
      - Incident (Box 37)
      - India (Box 37)
      - Inside Dallas (Box 37)
      - Insides Like the Sea, for Peter Warshall (Box 37)
      - Interior Egg [with other poems attached] (Box 37)